

shantanu.patil09@gmail.com

shan-96.github.io/ 9158121986

♀ Pune

Aug. 2014 to May 2018

in /in/shantanu-patil-21a42b121/ nshan-96

EDUCATION

National Institute of Technology Delhi

B.Tech Computer Science and Engineering

CGPA - 8.17

Springboard AI/ML Career Track

Aug. 2019 to Mar. 2020 Mastered skills in the machine learning stack, including data wrangling at scale, deep learning, and building and deploying large-scale AI systems.

SUMMARY

Self motivated software developer with knowledge of financial markets and healthcare. Currently exploring big data both within industry and through individual projects. Published author on Springr. Has worked on multiple data science and AI projects right from undergraduate level. Experienced in all aspects of SDLC and knowledge of building high performance applications in java and python.

SKILLS

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES: Python, Java, Scala, C++, SQL FRAMEWORKS & LIBRARIES: Tensorflow, Scikit-Learn, Pandas, Dask, TPOT, AutoML, Spark, Avro, Spring, PyMC3, Hazelcast TECHNOLOGIES & SERVICES: AWS, GCP, ELK, PowerBI, Jenkins

EMPLOYMENT

TRIPLE POINT TECHNOLOGY, ION GROUP

Software Developer

- Working on heavy throughput risk management engine
- Created Spark and Avro based Reconciliation Tool

FIDELITY INTERNATIONAL

Software Development Intern

• Worked on Investment recommendation engine for entry level fund managers

Pune, Maharashtra, India June 2018 to Current

Gurugram, Haryana, India June 2017 to July 2017

PROJECTS

PREDICTING FRAUD IN FINANCIAL PAYMENT SERVICES

From a Kaggle dataset determine and build a fraud detection model for Payment Data of online users for financial services https://www.kaggle.com/ntnutestimon/paysim1

GESTURE IDENTIFICATION FROM VIDEOS

A combination of SVM and GAN to determine gestures in groups of people to identify rioters and stone pelters via frame by frame motion capture of videos

WIKI LANGUAGE MODEL USING LSTM

An LSTM Neural Network for wiki topics and auto generating paragraphs for them

FLASK BASED AWS ELASTICBEANSTALK API FOR SUPER-RESOLUTION IMAGING

A flask API to convert your local low-resolution image to high resolution compatible with mobile browsers and fully responsive UI that gives results in real time

LABEL LEARNING WITH LSTM AND ULMFIT

This project scraps comments from JIRA tickets on a web portal and labels them with proper resolution taken

MUTLILEVEL SVM FOR CANCER DETECTION

Cancer Detection Algorithm with Hierarchical Multi modelled SVM

SENTIMENT ANALYSIS WITH NAMED ENTITY RECOGNITION

Find sentiment and entity names of text review using NLTK in python

RFM ANALYSIS USING GOOGLE ANALYTICS BIG QUERY EXPORT SCHEMA

A demonstrative RFM analysis using Big Query to understand customer segmentation

PUBLICATIONS

AUTHOR · Springr Publications

Medical Diagnosis of Ailments Through Supervised Learning Techniques on Sounds of the Heart and Lungs, Soft Computing and Signal Processing Vol 2, 2018

VOLUNTEERING

BHUMI.ORG · Centre Coodinator PCMC School, Pune

May 2019 to Current